Contact

ellie.tt.chen@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/elliettchen (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Microsoft Office Leadership Project Management

Languages

Taiwanese Hokkien (Native or Bilingual)

English (Native or Bilingual)

Mandarin (Native or Bilingual)

Ellie Chen

Coder at Coder Academy

Sydney, Australia

Summary

I have more than 3-years' professional experience in the migration industry, specialising in individual migration and accounting skills assessment. Throughout my career, I feel most fulfilled when I exercise my bilingual communication skills and migration knowledge in helping people to achieve their goals in lives.

Currently, I'm studying full-stack web development with Coder Academy and hoping to land a job as a developer in the near future.

Experience

Chartered Accountants Australia and New Zealand 3 years 1 month

Migration Executive January 2017 - August 2019 (2 years 8 months) Sydney, Australia

- Carrying out the complex migration assessment for skilled employment and overseas qualifications.
- Identifying training needs, producing internal training materials on CRM systems (Salesforce and NetSuite), and providing ongoing assessment training and technical support to other assessors.
- Advising on difficult migration assessment issues, interpreting migration legislation and the latest policy changes, and providing executive support and strategic advice to Migration Specialist.
- Awarded CA ANZ Scholarship in May 2017 for leadership potential and professional development.

Migration Coordinator August 2016 - December 2016 (5 months) Sydney, Australia

- Conducting standard migration assessment with high attention to details, and providing tailored application advice to individual applicants and migration agents with a strong customer focus.

- Proven time-management skills in handling high volumes of applications, prioritising tasks, meeting deadlines, and working autonomously and cooperatively in a high-performing professional team.

Ausky Visa Solutions
Assistant Migration Consultant
September 2014 - July 2016 (1 year 11 months)
Sydney, Australia

- Started as a part-time role while studying in Sydney, and later worked my way up to a full-time Assistant Migration Consultant with extensive experience in various types of visa.
- Preparing applications for Employer Sponsored Migration (457/ENS/RSMS), General Skilled Migration, Partner and Student Visas, and maintaining a 95% visa approval rate.
- Efficiently managing a client's visa application from the initial engagement, eligibility assessment, follow-up correspondence, application lodgement to final decision.
- Effectively facilitating the communication between the mandarin-speaking clients and other English-speaking parties, including Immigration case officers and skills assessing authorities.

Weasto Translation Company
Localisation Project Manager and Translator
July 2010 - June 2011 (1 year)
Taipei City, Taiwan

- Intelligently organising translation projects, conducting human resource deployment of in-house/freelance translators and editors, and liaising with international clients and local vendors.
- Effectively managing a one-million-words Expedia.com project and achieving scheduled goals.
- Produced high-quality translation and met deadlines consistently.
- Specialised translation in information technology products (e.g. Apple, HP, Canon and Fuji Xerox) and travelling websites (e.g. Expedia.com and W Hotels & Resorts).
- Subsequently contracted as a freelance translator (Jul 2011 Jan 2015).

Education

Coder Academy

The Australian National University

Graduate Certificate of Australian Migration Law and Practice, Migration Law \cdot (2017 - 2017)

Victoria University

Graduate Diploma in Professional Accounting · (2015 - 2016)

Macquarie University

Postgraduate Diploma of Translating and Interpreting, Translating and Interpreting · (2014 - 2015)

National Taiwan Normal University

Master of Translation and Interpreting, Translation (Chinese - English) \cdot (2013 - 2014)